飞
出
个
飞
未
来
你若不看 自有人看
个
出
未
来
飞
出
个
未
来
字幕显示如有问题 请使用srt版本
■
动中之动
指正：downforwater@gmail.com  twitter:@DownforWater
第六季第 七 集
本字幕参考了The Inforsphere以及PEEL
英文版字幕由n17t01制作 一版
■
嘘 别吵醒了Fry
Shh! Don't wake up Fry.
嘘 我室友在睡觉
Shh! My roommate's sleeping!
快起来 嗯？
- Wake up already! - Huh?
我就要与这位机器女士共度良宵了
I'm about to get down and funky with this Ladybot,
弄得尽人皆知 才对我胃口
and I'd appreciate it if as many people as possible could know about it.
你现在少给我八卦
Now can we get some privacy?!
啊 嘢 再来
Aw, yeah! Back it on up.
Hambone(一种即兴音乐)
♪ Hambone, hambone! ♪
Hambone
♪ Hambone! ♪
好嘞 Hambone演出结束
Okay, hambone break's over.
回卧室
Back to the bedroom!
Hambone
♪ Hambone, hambone! ♪
♪ Hambone! ♪
起来享受咖啡
Wake up and feel the coffee!
哦 不 我上班又迟了
Oh, no, I'm late for work again!
对不起 我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
好啊 好啊 好啊
Well, well, well.
瞧瞧谁大驾光临了
Look who decided to show up.
我受够了你的拖拉 Fry
I've had it with your tardiness, Fry.
我指望你能像别人一样按时上班
I expect you to arrive the same time as everyone else.
等等 Leela也没来啊
Well, wait a second. Leela's not here yet.
人家走了有一会儿了
She left a while ago.
她说她过生日有个白痴要请她吃午饭
She said some idiot was taking her to lunch for her birthday.
哦 不 我晚了
Oh, no, I'm late!
既然你被放了鸽子
Since you got stood up,
我觉着这样能给你提提神
I thought this might cheer you up a notch.
没必要
That's not necessary.
今天是什么日子
♪ What day is today? ♪
-今天是Leela的生日
- ♪ It's Leela's birthday ♪
请停下来
- ♪ It's Leela's birthday ♪ - Please stop.
多好的一个生日
♪ What a day for a birthday ♪
真麻烦你别唱了
I really would like you to stop singing.
咱们一起来点蛋糕
♪ Let's all have some cake! ♪
要不要来一块 $11.95的生日蛋糕
You want to buy a slice of birthday cake for $11.95?
好 有劳您了
Yes, please.
蛋糕不错啊
Uh, nice cake.
对不住 我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
你哪疯去...?!
Where have you...?!
唉 算了
Uh! It's fine.
你不生气？
You're not mad?
我是生气来着 不过有又想到
I was. But then I realized
幻想你能准时实际上是我的错
it's actually my fault for thinking you might be on time for once.
总之 我吃了双份午餐
Anyhow, I ate both our lunches.
你点了份龙虾
You ordered the lobster pileup.
可不便宜
It wasn't cheap.
行行好 让我补偿你
Please, let me make it up to you.
我带你到绿地溶洞 去好好吃顿生日晚餐
I'll treat you to a fancy birthday dinner tonight at Cavern on the Green.
哇 那绝对会是我被放鸽子的地方之中最好的一个
Wow, that'll be the nicest place I've ever been stood up.
不会再犯了
Not this time.
无论如何 我保证我会准时
No matter what happens, I swear I'll be there.
弟兄们 弟兄们
Guys, guys!
Hedonismbot总算要安定下来
Hedonismbot is finally gonna settle down
又在郊区找了个房子老婆
and marry a nice house in the suburbs!
不过今晚
But tonight,
他要开一个史上最疯狂的单身聚会
he's having the girls gone wildest bachelor party of all time!
唔-我-我 才不管
Whoo-who-who... cares?
我要和Leela共进晚餐
I'm having dinner with Leela.
就去你那个破聚会吧
Just go to your stupid party.
生日晚餐咱可以在某年某月再吃
We can have dinner on my birthday some other year.
不 我啥时候都能吐在脱衣舞娘身上
No! I can throw up on a stripper anytime.
今晚 我不要吐
Tonight, I want to not throw up...
在你身上
On you.
真的？
Really?
你别后悔
Your loss.
嘿 教授 我的战友就你了
Hey, Professor, you're my wingman!
很好
Very well.
Cubert 把喝酒的假牙拿来
Cubert, fetch my drinking teeth.
我只要在Leela的生日卡上签个名就成了
I just have to sign Leela's birthday card.
“拥吻”咋写？
How do you spell "XO"?
Guh!
这是个录像卡
It's a record-your-own-message card.
不用你签 只用录个裸体问候
You don't sign it. You leave a nude video greeting.
非得是裸体吗？
Does it have to be nude?
可能不用 我还真没想过这茬
I guess not. That never occurred to me.
只要我这就走人 在路上录一个生日问候
If I leave now, record a birthday greeting on the way,
再在报摊那整点香水
score some fancy cologne at the newsstand,
我准能按时抵达
I'll be exactly on time.
哪都别想去
You're not going anywhere!
但我有个约会啊
But I have a date.
你今早迟到了
You were late this morning,
所以你必须留下来测试我的最新发明
so you have to stay and test my latest invention!
瞧
Behold!
时光机器
A time-traveling machine!
时光? 我可不能回去
Time? I can't go back there!
啊 不过这台时光机器只能在时间里前进
Ah, but this time machine only goes forward in time!
这样的话就省得你意外改变历史了
That way you can't accidentally change history
或者做些龊事 好比跟自己奶奶上床
or do something disgusting, like sleep with your own grandmother.
我也不想再失足了
I wouldn't want to do that again.
我们会前进一分钟测试一下
We're going to test it by going forward in time one minute.
上去
Get in.
好吧 赶快 早了早好
Okay, hurry. Let's get it over with.
我就在机器里录Leela的生日卡
I can record Leela's birthday card while we're in there.
生日快乐 Leela
Happy Birthday, Leela!
很对不起我要迟到一分钟
I'm really sorry I'm gonna be one minute late,
因为我们要测试教授的破时间机器
'cause we're testing the Professor's dumb time machine,
好 我只需把我们向前推动正好一分钟
I'll just nudge us forward exactly one minute into the...
哇
Whoa!
我的卡
My card!
咱是不是走过了？
Did we go too far?!
现在是啥时候？
What time is it?!
公元一万年
The year 10,000.
哦 天
Oh, dear.
我是说 哦 乖乖
I mean, oh, my.
一万年?
The year 10,000?!
但是我对Leela保证过我不会迟到的
But I promised Leela I'd be on time for dinner!
放松 Fry
Relax, Fry.
所有咱认识的人都死了几千年了
Everyone we ever knew died thousands of years ago.
所有咱认识的?
Everyone we ever knew?
啊 反正我也没喜欢过那些家伙
Ah, I never liked those guys.
不  他们做到了
No! They did it!
他们搞砸了
They blew it up!
然后人猿也把他们的社会搞砸了
And then the apes blew up their society, too!
怎么会这样
How could this happen?!
鸟儿们接管后也搞砸了
And then the birds took over and ruined their society!</i>
还有牛 还有...
And the cows, and then...
我不认识也许是个鼻涕虫？
I don't know. Is that a slug maybe?
不
No...!
绿地溶洞 3010年
CAVERN ON THE GREEN THE YEAR 3010
在您等待您朋友的同时
While you await your "friend,"
请允许我向您介绍我们岩洞的历史
allow me to read from a prepared history of our cavern.
千万年来由洞顶滴下的
These unique rock formations
矿物质水形成
were created over millions of years
了这罕有的岩石构造
by mineral-rich water dripping from pores in the ceiling.
滴而又滴 年复一年
Dripping and dripping, year upon year,
世纪复世纪...
Century upon century...
今天是什么日子
♪ What day is today? ♪
嘿 你不是昨儿个在我的分店
Hey, aren't you the loser who got stood up
被放鸽子的那个矬人吗
at my other restaurant?
给我闭嘴再给我上双份晚餐
Just shut up and bring me two dinners.
有谁见着Fry的屁股了吗？
Has anyone seen Fry's ass?
我的靴子可等他等得急了
It's late for a date with my boot.
Fry不在这儿
Fry's not here.
肯定他跟Bender和教授
Obviously, he went to that pervert party 去那个变态聚会了
with Bender and the Professor.
Fry去聚会了?
Fry went to the party?
我们打断 冰上催眠 的播出
We interrupt Hypnotoad On Ice</i>
为您带来一起灾难的突发新闻
to bring you breaking coverage
事件发生于Hedonismbot的单身聚会上
of the disaster at Hedonismbot's bachelor party.
Linda 今夜一场天真无邪的欢乐
Linda, what began as innocent fun
悲剧地止于一个
ended in tragedy tonight
核动力脱衣舞娘的反应堆灾难性的融毁
when a nuclear-powered robot stripper suffered a catastrophic reactor meltdown.
只有一名生还者
There is only one survivor.
我所见之处 一片肉林
Everywhere I looked, there were piles of bodies.
接着便发生了爆炸
And then the explosion struck.
我所敬爱的三位同事全死了
The three co-workers I liked are all dead!
Fry放了我的鸽子居然还死了
Fry stood me up and died?!
气死我也
I'm so angry!
我是说 我悲从中来
I mean, I'm so sad!
不过 又实在气死我也
But-but I'm still pretty angry!
却又十分悲哀
But also sad.
我能兼而有之吗？
Can I be both?
那绝对会是Fry的遗愿
It's what he'd want.
那这就是我此刻的心情了
Then that's what I am!
唉 这未来简直霉气透顶
Man, the future is a total craphole,
谁活在这儿简直倒了八辈子的霉
and whoever lives here is a crap-faced sack of crap!
没恶意 哥们
No offense, fellas.
没事 弟兄
Don't sweat it, man.
我再也见不到Leela了
I'll never see Leela again.
是的 没有时光倒转机
No, without a backwards time machine,
咱们就被困在这破地儿了
we're stuck in this craphole.
-伙计 省省吧 -且慢
Dude, give it a rest. Hold on.
有主意了
I've got it!
我们不能让时光倒流
We can't go back in time,
但是我们能一直向前
but we can keep going forward
直到有人发明了时光倒转机
until people invent the backwards time machine.
然后我们就能回家了
And then we can go home.</i>
高
Hit it.
在105105年
♪ In the year 105105 ♪
人类是否生还
♪ If man is still alive ♪
机器人是否尚存
♪ If robot can survive ♪
他们或发现
♪ They may find... ♪
在252525年
♪ In the year 252525 ♪
时光倒转机仍未降临
♪ The backwards time machine still won't have arrived ♪
举世只存一技
♪ In all the world, there's only one technology ♪
一把修理直肠的锈剑
♪ A rusty sword for practicing proctology ♪
在未来那以20结尾的一年
♪ In a future year that ends with 20 ♪
一个邋遢的人鱼在找知己
♪ A shlubby merman's gonna try to get chummy ♪
他也许看起来好似湿嗒嗒的傻帽
♪ He may look like a watery wimp ♪
事实上确是嗜血的巨虾
♪ When in fact he's a bloodthirsty shrimp! ♪
在那一百又五十万年
♪ In the year one million and a half ♪
全人类被长颈鹿奴役
♪ Humankind is enslaved by giraffe ♪
人类必须赎罪
♪ Man must pay for all his misdeeds ♪
当树梢被剥去最后一片树叶
♪ When the treetops are stripped of their leaves ♪
哇-哦-哦
♪ Whoa-oa-oa. ♪
有时真无法相信教授被杀后 星球快递在你的管理下
Sometimes I can't believe how successful Planet Express became
竟变得如此成功
once the Professor was killed and you seized control.
原来日子再苦 咱么也齐心协力
There were tough times, but we all pulled together.
我一直在核算咱们的跨星际战略
I've been crunching the numbers on our trans-galactic strategy...
你在这儿作甚?
What are you doing here?
我20年前就把你炒了
I laid you off 20 years ago.
唉 这爪子也不如以前好使了
Oh, the claws can't flee like they used to.
成功固然好
Success is nice,
不过我确实还有些怀旧
but I do kind of miss the old days.
嘿 Leels.
Hey, Leels.
嗨 Cubert.
Hi, Cubert.
何以效劳 陌生人?
May we help you, strange ones?
我们是来自过去的时间旅行者 小不点
We are travelers from the past, my good runt.
明白
I see.
自你那时起 人类进化便分道扬镳
Since your time, human evolution has diverged.
我们这一支 聪明绝顶 厚德载物
There are we... advanced in intellect and morality...
Dumblocks 那一支 愚不可及 凶狠残暴 居住在地下
And the Dumblocks... stupid, vicious brutes who live underground.
聪明绝顶 您刚说?
Advanced in intellect, you say?
那你们是否发明出了时光倒转机?
Have you invented a backwards time machine?
没有 不过一旦我们开动那非凡的智慧
No, but if we apply our superior minds,
五年之内我们就可以完善那样的装置
we could perfect such a device within five years.
回见
See you then!
我们来取时间机器啦
We're back for our time machine!
呦呼 孩子们
Yoo-hoo, boys!
这个时代在人类历史又是如何?
What's this era in human history like?
那些我们制造的
The machines...
用来服务人类的机器
We built them to make our lives easier,
都造反了
but they rebelled.
它们不把人类赶尽杀绝就不停休
They won't stop until every human is dead.
这段未来看起来还不赖
This seems like a nice future.
咱们干脆留下来得了
Let's just stay here.
咱们可以在那座骷髅山上安营
We could settle down on that mountain of skulls.
嘿 那里能把 美丽的血湖尽收眼底
Hey! That place had a gorgeous view of Blood Lake!
好啊 时间旅行者
Greetings, time travelers.
两个蠢货
Stupid jerks!
不许我待在我自在的未来
Wouldn't let me stay in the good future.
你们咋知道我们是时间旅行者?
How did you know we're time travelers?
我们也研究时间旅行之秘
We, too, study the time travel enigma.
我们发明了一向利用反中微子场的方法
We have perfected a method using negative-mass neutrino fields that
使我们可以在时间中逆向旅行
allows us to travel backwards in time.
我叫Hubert.
My name's Hubert.
好嘞 咱们可以回家啦
All right! We can go home!
好嘞 咱们可以回...
All right! We can go...
我们不妨明日探讨探讨
We can talk of our research tomorrow.
男人在我们的社会里十分稀少
Men are very rare in our society.
即便非常年老的和愚笨的男性都很难得
Even very old and stupid males are prized.
今晚 请作为上宾参加我们的生育宴会
Tonight, please be the guests of honor at our fertility banquet.
参加个生育宴会自然是无妨
Well, there's certainly no harm in a fertility banquet.
我会吃
I could eat.
也能生育
And fertilize.
太好了
Very well.
让我们以不上手的方式给我们的贵客擦油
Let us anoint our guests in oil without using our hands.
哦 就只许州官放火
Oh, so we can stay in the future you like,
不许百姓点灯啊?
but not the future I like?
走
Next!
不
No!
我差一点就成功了
I was about to close the deal!
Bender她们有时光倒转机
Bender, they had a backwards time machine!
别的地方也有好玩意儿
The other place had a lot of good things, too!
你看见那个骷髅山了吗?
Did you even see that mountain of skulls?
为甚 你
Why, you!
哦 不 你别想
Oh, no, you didn't.
住手
Stop!
某处 某时 Leela在等我
Somewhere, some time, Leela is waiting for me.
咱们得接着找时光倒转机
We need to keep looking for a backwards time machine.
Fry说得对
Fry's right.
不错 咱们必须合作
Yes. We have to work together,
而不是打这种我必胜的架
not have this fight, which I was definitely winning.
公元十亿年
The year one billion.
我琢磨着
I've got a feeling
这就是咱们要找的时间点
this could be exactly the point in time we've been looking for!
不
Nope.
事实上 所有生命都已灭亡
In fact, all life is extinct.
那咱们接着前进
So let's keep going forward.
哦 没必要了
Oh, it's no use.
地球已死
Earth is dead.
这就是万物的尽头
This is the end of all things.
绿地溶洞
The Cavern on the Green.
我来了 Leela.
I made it, Leela.
对不起 我晚了十亿年
Sorry I'm a billion years late.
亲爱的FRY
DEAR FRY
你会拿到你那份赡养费的 Cubert.
You'll get your alimony check, Cubert.
立马走开
Now get lost!
别急
Chill out.
我只不过来找Amy
I'm just here to see Amy.
走啦 小可爱
Move it, boy toy.
奶奶带你去亚特兰大
Granny's taking you to Atlantic City.
真搞不明白你原先怎么会嫁给那个猪鼻混混
I don't know why you ever married that pig-nosed punk.
我也不明白
I don't know, either.
我现在就算嫁给工作了
I'm married to the job now.
我原先觉着总会有个白马王子 但...
I used to think there was someone for me, but...
怪了
How odd.
这是那种老式的录像生日卡
It's one of those old record-your-own-message birthday cards.
生日快乐 Leela
Happy Birthday, Leela!
很对不起我要迟到一分钟
I'm really sorry I'm gonna be one minute late,
因为我们要测试教授的破时间机器
'cause we're testing the Professor's dumb time machine...
不过 啊 你晓得
But, uh, you know,
生日快乐 而且 呃...
happy birthday and all, and, uh...
我爱你
I love you.
我的卡
My card!
我气了他一辈子
My whole life I've been mad at him,
到头来却不是他的错
and it wasn't his fault.
亲爱的Fry 你我聚少离多
Dear Fry, our time together was short
但那是我生命中最宝贵的时光
but it was the best time of my life.
其实 说到底 我这辈子活得不错
You know, all in all, I had a good life.
你们说咱仨来点啤酒
What do you say the three of us grab a six-pack
再一起看宇宙终结咋样?
and watch the universe end?
同意 同意
Hear! Hear!
老子基本上每天都那样过
That's basically what I do every day.
敬宇宙终结
To the end of the universe!
别了 地球
So long, Earth.
谢谢空气那啥的
Thanks for the air and whatnot.
嘿 呃 生命的意义到底是啥?
Hey, uh, what was the purpose of life, anyway?
谁晓得
Who knows.
也许压根就是瞎扯些人类精神
Probably some hogwash about the human spirit.
差不离
Mm-hmm. Sounds about right.
星光在减弱
The stars are receding.
哦 无尽的空虚
Oh, the vast emptiness!
嘢 嘢 我晓得你是啥意思
Yeah, yeah, I can take a hint.
最后一颗质子这会儿就该消散了
The last proton should be decaying about now.
再见 最后的质子
Bye, last proton.
而 这就是
And... here we are.
寰宇之终
The end of the universe.
那 现在咋样?
Well, now what?
要不要说说闲话?
You guys want to talk?
不 谢了
No, thanks.
你们都看见了吗?!
Did anyone else see that?!
不可思议
Unbelievable!
第二次宇宙大爆炸
It's a second big bang!
老天爷 这可能吗?
My God, is it possible?
绝对可能 这不就在眼皮底下吗
It must be possible. It's happening.
顺便问一句 这是啥?
By the way, what's happening?
似乎这个宇宙同上一个完全相同
It appears this universe is exactly identical to the old one.
果真如此的话 我们只需继续向前时间旅行
If so, we just need to keep going forward in time
就能回到咱们离开的时候
to the point when we left!
地球诞生了
The Earth is born!
女士们 先生们 月球
Ladies and gentlemen, the moon!
看 第一条爬上陆地的鱼
Look. The first fish to crawl up on land.
它可是径直朝我们爬过来了 你瞅着了
It was coming right at us! You saw it.
我要再来罐啤酒
I'm gonna grab another beer.
Fry Fry 你要错过恐龙了
Fry, Fry, you're missing the dinosaurs!
没事 它们又跑不掉
It's okay. They're not going anywhere.
它们跑哪去了?
Where'd they go?
这会儿又在发生啥?
Now, what's going on there?
历史
History.
慢着 我要停一站
Hang on. I just want to make one stop.
看看我的小胡子(德语)
Betrachten sie meinen schnurrbart!
稳住 不急
Easy. Easy.
控制她着陆
Taking her in for a landing.
还差一年
One year to go.
六个月
Six months.
我快到了 Leela
I'm almost there, Leela.
一个月 两个星期
One month... two weeks...
一个小时...
One hour...
30秒...
30 seconds...
这就要...
And here we...
停
Stop!
给我钥匙 啊呀
Give me the keys, Magoo!
咱们只有再来一遍了
We'll have to bring her around again.
悠着点 我从窗口狙击希特勒
Just slow it down. I'll shoot Hitler out the window.
糟 我错打中了埃莉诺·罗斯福
Darn! I hit Eleanor Roosevelt by mistake.
好 又快到咱们的时代了
Okay, nearing our era again.
这就来啦
Here we go.
小心这次
Careful this time.
小心
Careful.
我们会前进一分钟以测试这台机器
We're going to test it by going forward in time one minute.
上车
Get in.
好吧 赶快 早了早好
Okay. Hurry. Let's get it over with.
这个新宇宙比咱们的老宇宙要矮十尺
This new universe is about ten feet lower than our old one.
哈 我们解决了时间旅行悖论
Pow! We took care of the time travel paradox.
-好啊 -万岁
All right! Hooray!
啊哦 和Leela的晚餐我要迟到了
Uh-oh. I'm late for dinner with Leela.
欢迎光临绿地溶洞
Welcome to Cavern on the Green.
在您等待的同时是否愿意来些肉馅糕?
May I offer you some meat loaf while you wait?
我迟到了对不起
Sorry I'm late!
事实上 你刚好准点
Actually, you're on time.
真的?
Really?
我得承认我原先恐怕你又要晚了
I have to admit, I was afraid you wouldn't make it.
那是旧Fry
That was the old Fry.
他已经死了
He's dead now.
生日快乐 Leela.
Happy Birthday, Leela.
我本来给你准备了张卡 但我可能弄丢了
I got you a card, but I guess I kind of lost it.
没关系 我也不怎么喜欢卡片
That's okay. I don't really like cards.
我所会记住的是和你在一起的时光
What I'll remember is our time together.